[
    {
        "Question":"A 36-year-old man falls on his outstretched right hand. Examination reveals tenderness in the anatomical snuffbox. Which of the following tendons forms a boundary of the anatomical snuffbox",
        "Option 1":"Abductor pollicis brevis",
        "Option 2":"Extensor carpi radialis brevis",
        "Option 3":"Extensor carpi radialis longus",
        "Option 4":"Extensor indices",
        "Option 5":"Extensor pollicis longus",
        "Correct Answer":"Extensor pollicis longus"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 26-year-old man presents to the ED with extensive bleeding from his arm after sustaining a glass injury. On examination there\u2019s a 7 cm transverse laceration across the anterior aspect of his elbow. On exploring the cubital fossa, you expect the brachial artery to be:",
        "Option 1":"Anterior to the median nerve",
        "Option 2":"Lateral to the biceps tendon",
        "Option 3":"Lateral to the median nerve",
        "Option 4":"Medial to the median nerve",
        "Option 5":"Superficial to the bicipital aponeurosis",
        "Correct Answer":"Lateral to the median nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"An 80-year-old man dislocates his shoulder and got it reduced in the emergency department at review three weeks later, he\u2019s unable to initiate abduction of his arm. Which muscle is most likely to be affected?",
        "Option 1":"Clavicular head of pectoralis minor",
        "Option 2":"Infraspinatus",
        "Option 3":"Supraspinatus",
        "Option 4":"Teres major",
        "Option 5":"Trapezius",
        "Correct Answer":"Supraspinatus"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 20-year old man presents to the emergency department with a stab injury to the thenar eminence . on examination, he is found to have a 2 cm long laceration with loss of sensation in the thumb and index finger and weakness of the thenar muscles. Which of the following structures is most likely to be injured?",
        "Option 1":"Anterior interosseus nerve",
        "Option 2":"Recurrent branch of median nerve",
        "Option 3":"Sensory and motor branches of median nerve",
        "Option 4":"Sensory and motor branches of radial nerve",
        "Option 5":"sensory and motor branches of ulnar nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Sensory and motor branches of median nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"in order to expose the right axillary artery, a transverse incision is typically made below the clavicle from a point just lateral to the sternal end of the clavicle to the deltopectoral groove. Which of the following structures would be encountered in the dissection down to the vessel?",
        "Option 1":"Lateral thoracic artery",
        "Option 2":"Phrenic nerve",
        "Option 3":"Suprascapular artery",
        "Option 4":"Thoracic duct",
        "Option 5":"Throacoacromial artery",
        "Correct Answer":"Throacoacromial artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 4-year-old boy is brought to the emergency room with painful right elbow. His father states that he was swinging his son by his arms when the pain came on suddenly. An X-ray shows that the radial head is displaced from its usual position. What is the ligament of the proximal radioulnar joint that holds the radial head in place?",
        "Option 1":"Annular ligament",
        "Option 2":"Conoid ligament",
        "Option 3":"Quadrate ligament",
        "Option 4":"Radial ligament",
        "Option 5":"Ulnar ligament",
        "Correct Answer":"Annular ligament"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 26-year-old man presents to the emergency department after sustaining a glass cut to his arm. On examination there\u2019s a 10 cm longitudinal laceration on the anterior aspect of the upper arm. He has symptoms suggestive of ulnar nerve injury. On exploring the upper part of the arm. We would expect the ulnar nerve to be:",
        "Option 1":"Anterior then medial to the brachial artery",
        "Option 2":"Medial then anterior to the brachial artery",
        "Option 3":"Medial to the brachial artery",
        "Option 4":"Posterior then medial to the brachial artery",
        "Option 5":"posterior to the brachial artery",
        "Correct Answer":"Medial to the brachial artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"a 19-year-old woman presents to the emergency department profoundly hypovolemic having fallen from a horse. A postero-anterior chest radiograph shows fracture to the medial third of the left clavicle. Which of the following vessels is most likely to be damaged?",
        "Option 1":"Brachiocephalic trunk",
        "Option 2":"Left axillary artery",
        "Option 3":"Left common carotid artery",
        "Option 4":"Left subclavian artery",
        "Option 5":"Left vertebral vein",
        "Correct Answer":"Left subclavian artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 20-year-old man presents to the emergency department after accidentally tripping over and leacerating his hand on a glass bottle. On examination there\u2019s a 2 cm laceration on the hypothenar eminence with loss of flexion in the distal interphalangeal joint of the little finger what is the most likely tendon to be injured?",
        "Option 1":"Flexor digiti minimi brevis",
        "Option 2":"Flexor digitorum profundus",
        "Option 3":"Flexor digitorum superficialis",
        "Option 4":"Fourth palmer interossei",
        "Option 5":"Lumbricals",
        "Correct Answer":"Flexor digitorum profundus"
    },
    {
        "Question":"After the mastectomy the woman has winging of the scapula, what is the nerve being injured?",
        "Option 1":"Long thoracic nerve",
        "Option 2":"Thoracodorsal nerve",
        "Option 3":"Spinal accessory nerve",
        "Option 4":"Suprascapular nerve",
        "Option 5":"Axillary nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Long thoracic nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 50-year-old alcoholic man presents to the emergency room and is found to be unable to extend his wrist, thumb and fingers of his right hand, he is also found to have weak extension of his right elbow and loss of sensation on the dorsum of the first web space. Which nerve is most likely to have been injured",
        "Option 1":"Median nerve",
        "Option 2":"Musculocutaneous nerve",
        "Option 3":"Posterior interosseus nerve",
        "Option 4":"Radial nerve",
        "Option 5":"Ulnar nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Radial nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 36-year-old butcher injures his left index finger with a knife, suffering a deep laceration on the palmer aspect of the thumb on examination, he is unable to flex DIP of the thumb, which tendon is likely to have been injured?",
        "Option 1":"Flexor carpi facialis",
        "Option 2":"Flexor pollicis brevis",
        "Option 3":"Flexor digitorum profundus",
        "Option 4":"Flexor digitorum superficialis",
        "Option 5":"Flexor pollicis longus",
        "Correct Answer":"Flexor pollicis longus"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 58-year-old man is due to have surgery for dupuytrens contracture to release the ring finger of the right hand. Which of the following regarding the anatomy of the ring finger is correct?",
        "Option 1":"Has a cutaneous innervation form the radial nerve",
        "Option 2":"Has no cutaneous innervation from the median nerve",
        "Option 3":"Has no cutaneous innervation from the ulnar nerve",
        "Option 4":"Has the flexor digitorum profundus inserting into the middle phlanx",
        "Option 5":"Is abducted by a palmer interosseus muscle",
        "Correct Answer":"Has a cutaneous innervation form the radial nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A patient presents to the clinic following a surgical procedure. She complains that she is unable to shrug her shoulder. What is the most likely underlying nerve injury?",
        "Option 1":"Accessory nerve",
        "Option 2":"Cervical plexus",
        "Option 3":"Ansa cervicalis",
        "Option 4":"Long thoracic nerve",
        "Option 5":"Axillary nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Accessory nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 33-year-old man sustains an injury to his forearm and wrist. When examined in clinic he is unable to adduct his thumb. What is the most likely underlying nerve lesion?",
        "Option 1":"Radial nerve",
        "Option 2":"Superficial branch of the ulnar nerve",
        "Option 3":"Median nerve",
        "Option 4":"Posterior interosseus",
        "Option 5":"Deep branch of the ulnar nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Deep branch of the ulnar nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the nerve supply of the dorsal interossei of the fourth finger?",
        "Option 1":"Radial nerve",
        "Option 2":"Median nerve",
        "Option 3":"Superficial ulnar nerve",
        "Option 4":"Deep ulnar nerve",
        "Option 5":"Posterior intreosseous nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Deep ulnar nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 23-year-old patient was admitted to after falling of his outstretched hand. His examination revealed that he has lost sensation over the palmer aspect of the index and middle finger. What is the most likely cause of this injury?",
        "Option 1":"Hook of hamate fracture",
        "Option 2":"Distal radial fracture",
        "Option 3":"Lunate dislocation",
        "Option 4":"Scaphoid fracture",
        "Option 5":"Monteggie fracture",
        "Correct Answer":"Lunate dislocation"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the dermatome of the little finger?",
        "Option 1":"C8",
        "Option 2":"C6",
        "Option 3":"C7",
        "Option 4":"T1",
        "Option 5":"C5",
        "Correct Answer":"C8"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the relation of ulnar nerve to the ulnar artery in the wrist?",
        "Option 1":"ulnar nerve is ulnar to the ulnar artery",
        "Option 2":"ulnar artery is ulnar to the ulnar nerve",
        "Option 3":"ulnar nerve is radial to the ulnar artery",
        "Option 4":"ulnar nerve is superficial to the ulnar artery",
        "Option 5":"none of the above",
        "Correct Answer":"ulnar nerve is ulnar to the ulnar artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"froment test is used for testing which of the following muscles?",
        "Option 1":"Abductor pollicis longus",
        "Option 2":"Abductor pollicis brevis",
        "Option 3":"Adductor pollicis",
        "Option 4":"Flexor carpi radialis",
        "Option 5":"Flexor pollicis longus",
        "Correct Answer":"Adductor pollicis"
    },
    {
        "Question":"During the posterior approach to humerus, what is the most common nerve to be injured?",
        "Option 1":"Radial nerve",
        "Option 2":"Median nerve",
        "Option 3":"Ulnar nerve",
        "Option 4":"Posterior interosseus nerve",
        "Option 5":"Anterior interosseus nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Radial nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the dermatome that give sensory supply over deltoid muscle?",
        "Option 1":"C5",
        "Option 2":"C4",
        "Option 3":"T1",
        "Option 4":"C7",
        "Option 5":"C8",
        "Correct Answer":"C5"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the root value responsible for sensation of the middle finger",
        "Option 1":"C6",
        "Option 2":"C4",
        "Option 3":"T1",
        "Option 4":"C7",
        "Option 5":"C8",
        "Correct Answer":"C7"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Head of radius articulates with",
        "Option 1":"Trochlea",
        "Option 2":"Olecranon fossa",
        "Option 3":"Capitulum",
        "Option 4":"Olecranon process",
        "Option 5":"None of the above",
        "Correct Answer":"Capitulum"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the nerve supply to the lateral side of the forearm?",
        "Option 1":"Radial nerve",
        "Option 2":"Median nerve",
        "Option 3":"Ulnar nerve",
        "Option 4":"Musculocutaneous nerve",
        "Option 5":"Axillary nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Musculocutaneous nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the course of median nerve related to the brachial artery throughout the arm?",
        "Option 1":"Anterior then medial then lateral",
        "Option 2":"Lateral then medial then anterior",
        "Option 3":"Lateral then anterior then medial",
        "Option 4":"Posterior then medial",
        "Option 5":"None of the above",
        "Correct Answer":"Lateral then anterior then medial"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A patient suffered an injury extending from deltopectoral groove medially, which structure will not be affected?",
        "Option 1":"Throacoacromial artery",
        "Option 2":"Pectoralis major muscle",
        "Option 3":"Cephalic vein",
        "Option 4":"Shoulder joint capsule",
        "Option 5":"None of the above",
        "Correct Answer":"Shoulder joint capsule"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A patient had upper limb injury. During examination, sensation over the dorsal aspect of the medial hand was intact with prominent claw hand what is the level of nerve injury?",
        "Option 1":"Radial nerve injury at the axilla",
        "Option 2":"Ulnar nerve injury at the wrist",
        "Option 3":"Median nerve injury at the cubital fossa",
        "Option 4":"Ulnar nerve injury at the elbow",
        "Option 5":"None of the above",
        "Correct Answer":"Ulnar nerve injury at the wrist"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A patient was undergoing radial head surgery for a fracture. Postoperatively, there is lost fingers extension with intact sensation. What is the nerve most likely to be injured?",
        "Option 1":"Anterior interosseus nerve injury",
        "Option 2":"Posterior interosseus nerve injury",
        "Option 3":"Radial nerve injury",
        "Option 4":"Superficial branch of radial nerve injury",
        "Option 5":"Ulnar nerve injury",
        "Correct Answer":"Posterior interosseus nerve injury"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A patient suffered a cut injury in the front of elbow joint. Which most lateral structure to be injured at this site?",
        "Option 1":"Biceps tendon",
        "Option 2":"Median nerve",
        "Option 3":"Brachial artery",
        "Option 4":"Ulnar nerve",
        "Option 5":"Anterior interosseus nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Biceps tendon"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A patient has weakness of the elbow extension with lost sensation over 1st digit dorsum which nerve involved?",
        "Option 1":"Anterior interosseus nerve injury",
        "Option 2":"Posterior interosseus nerve injury",
        "Option 3":"Radial nerve injury",
        "Option 4":"Superficial branch of radial nerve injury",
        "Option 5":"Ulnar nerve injury",
        "Correct Answer":"Radial nerve injury"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 32-year-old man suffered an injury to his palm resulting in loss sensation over hypothenar eminence, medial 1 and half finger, which nerve is involved?",
        "Option 1":"Deep ulnar nerve",
        "Option 2":"Palmer branch of radial nerve",
        "Option 3":"Posterior interosseus nerve",
        "Option 4":"Superficial ulnar nerve",
        "Option 5":"Median nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Superficial ulnar nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"The arterial blood supply to the scaphoid bone enters it from which end?",
        "Option 1":"Proximal pole",
        "Option 2":"Medial half",
        "Option 3":"Distal end",
        "Option 4":"Lateral side",
        "Option 5":"None of the above",
        "Correct Answer":"Distal end"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A patient had injury at wrist. Upon examination, hand was placed on the table with palm up, the patient can\u2019t make his thumb 90 degrees on the hand. Which muscle is involved?",
        "Option 1":"Adductor pollicis",
        "Option 2":"Abductor pollicis brevis",
        "Option 3":"Flexor pollicis longus",
        "Option 4":"Extensor pollicis longus",
        "Option 5":"Opponens pollicis",
        "Correct Answer":"Abductor pollicis brevis"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the dermatomal supply to the elbow, lateral forearm and thumb?",
        "Option 1":"C6",
        "Option 2":"C8",
        "Option 3":"T1",
        "Option 4":"T2",
        "Option 5":"C5",
        "Correct Answer":"C6"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 32-year-old patient presented with prominent claw hand with lost sensation over the medial arm. What is the spinal dermatome mostly affected?",
        "Option 1":"T1",
        "Option 2":"C7",
        "Option 3":"C6",
        "Option 4":"T2",
        "Option 5":"C5",
        "Correct Answer":"T1"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A man suffered a cut injury above the olecranon process cause loss of ability to extend elbow. Sensation is intact. What is the structure being affected?",
        "Option 1":"Triceps tendon",
        "Option 2":"Radial nerve",
        "Option 3":"Posterior interosseus nerve",
        "Option 4":"Median nerve",
        "Option 5":"Superficial branch of radial nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Triceps tendon"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A man suffered a deep injury just near olecranon with no elbow or wrist extension, with loss of sensation over the cleft between the thumb and index finger dorsally. What is the structure being damaged?",
        "Option 1":"Triceps tendon",
        "Option 2":"Radial nerve",
        "Option 3":"Posterior interosseus nerve",
        "Option 4":"Median nerve",
        "Option 5":"Superficial branch of radial nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Radial nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 35-year old patient has a wrist injury, and then developed thenar atrophy, what is the most likely affected nerve?",
        "Option 1":"Anterior interosseous nerve",
        "Option 2":"Radial nerve",
        "Option 3":"Posterior interosseous nerve",
        "Option 4":"Median nerve (recurrent branch)",
        "Option 5":"Superficial branch of median nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Median nerve (recurrent branch)"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the spinal center for arm supination?",
        "Option 1":"C5-6",
        "Option 2":"C4",
        "Option 3":"C6-7",
        "Option 4":"C7-8",
        "Option 5":"C8-T1",
        "Correct Answer":"C5-6"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A patient can\u2019t lift his thumb off the table while palm is facing downwards. Which is the most likely responsible nerve lesion?",
        "Option 1":"Anterior interosseus nerve",
        "Option 2":"Median nerve",
        "Option 3":"Posterior interosseus nerve",
        "Option 4":"Radial nerve",
        "Option 5":"None of the above",
        "Correct Answer":"Posterior interosseus nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A patient was undergoing surgical release of dupuytren\u2019s contracture at the ring finger while a nerve was injured just lateral to the deep flexor tendons of the ring finger. What is the nerve affected at this site?",
        "Option 1":"Superficial ulnar nerve",
        "Option 2":"Deep ulnar nerve",
        "Option 3":"Median nerve",
        "Option 4":"Radial nerve",
        "Option 5":"Posterior interosseus nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Median nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 2 day old neonate is brought by his mother with an upper limb deformity. On examination, his right arm is adducted while his forearm is extended and pronated, which of the following nerves is expected to be intact?",
        "Option 1":"Suprascapular nerve",
        "Option 2":"Musculocutaneous nerve",
        "Option 3":"Median nerve",
        "Option 4":"Medial pectoral nerve",
        "Option 5":"Lateral pectoral nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Medial pectoral nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 12 year old boy suffered a supracondylar humeral fracture. Which nerve is at greatest risk?",
        "Option 1":"Median nerve",
        "Option 2":"Ulnar nerve",
        "Option 3":"Posterior interosseus nerve",
        "Option 4":"Deep branch of ulnar nerve",
        "Option 5":"Anterior interosseus nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Anterior interosseus nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A patient developed ptosis and loss of sensation over the medial side of the arm after a shoulder injury. What is the responsible nerve root?",
        "Option 1":"C6",
        "Option 2":"C7",
        "Option 3":"C8",
        "Option 4":"C5",
        "Option 5":"T1",
        "Correct Answer":"T1"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 24 years old man suffered an injury to his upper limb. On examination, his ring and little fingers are partially flexed with intact sensation over the dorsal aspect of these fingers. What is the most likely lesion?",
        "Option 1":"Ulnar nerve at the wrist",
        "Option 2":"ulnar nerve at the elbow",
        "Option 3":"ulnar nerve at forearm",
        "Option 4":"median nerve",
        "Option 5":"radial nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"ulnar nerve at forearm"
    },
    {
        "Question":"a surgeon made an incision from below the clavicle to the deltopectoral groove. Which of the following structures will not be encountered?",
        "Option 1":"Roots of the brachial plexus",
        "Option 2":"Axillary vein",
        "Option 3":"Thoracoacromial artery",
        "Option 4":"Pectoralis minor insertion",
        "Option 5":"Pectoralis major",
        "Correct Answer":"Roots of the brachial plexus"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A woman suffered an arm injury. On examination she is unable to catch the knife as her hand moves into flexion. There is loss of sensation over the badge area. What is the likely cause?",
        "Option 1":"Radial nerve",
        "Option 2":"Axillary nerve",
        "Option 3":"Posterior cord injury",
        "Option 4":"Medial cord injury",
        "Option 5":"None of the above",
        "Correct Answer":"Posterior cord injury"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A patient has developed weakness in the intrinsic hand muscles with loss of sensation over the inner aspect of the arm. What is the most likely cause ?",
        "Option 1":"Ulnar nerve injury at the elbow",
        "Option 2":"Radial nerve injury",
        "Option 3":"Ulnar nerve injury at the wrist",
        "Option 4":"Superior sulcus tumor",
        "Option 5":"Anterior interosseus nerve injury",
        "Correct Answer":"Superior sulcus tumor"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 24-year-old man suffered an injury to the ulnar nerve during a fight. Which of the following thumb movement will be affected?",
        "Option 1":"Abduction",
        "Option 2":"Opposition",
        "Option 3":"Flexion",
        "Option 4":"Extension",
        "Option 5":"Adduction",
        "Correct Answer":"Adduction"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 32 year old man sustained an elbow trauma during his work. His examination revealed severe pain on extremes of pronation and supination. What is the most likely injured nerve?",
        "Option 1":"Radial nerve",
        "Option 2":"Anterior interosseus nerve",
        "Option 3":"Posterior interosseous nerve",
        "Option 4":"Median nerve",
        "Option 5":"Ulnar nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Posterior interosseous nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A patient presented with crutch related to the axilla , he has numbness over the lateral aspect of the forearm, which muscle will be affected as well?",
        "Option 1":"Brachialis",
        "Option 2":"Brachioradialis",
        "Option 3":"Flexor carpi radialis",
        "Option 4":"Pronator teres",
        "Option 5":"Triceps",
        "Correct Answer":"Brachialis"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Nerve injury following shoulder dislocation, deltoid is affected, which other muscle will be affected?",
        "Option 1":"Latissimus dorsi",
        "Option 2":"Teres minor",
        "Option 3":"Teres major",
        "Option 4":"Subscapularis",
        "Option 5":"Supraspinatus",
        "Correct Answer":"Teres minor"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the relation of extensor indices to extensor digitorum in index finger?",
        "Option 1":"Medial",
        "Option 2":"Lateral",
        "Option 3":"Posterior",
        "Option 4":"Anterior",
        "Option 5":"Medial then interior",
        "Correct Answer":"Medial"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 12 year old child presented after a trauma to his wrist . Xray is normal and he was discharged. He is now presenting back after one week with severe pain at anatomical snuffbox. What is the likely diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Lunate dislocation",
        "Option 2":"Scaphoid fracture",
        "Option 3":"Fracture distal ulna",
        "Option 4":"Carpal tunnel syndrome",
        "Option 5":"None of the above",
        "Correct Answer":"Scaphoid fracture"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A patient cannot hold a piece of paper between thumb and index fingers without flexion. The described deformity is a result of injury of which nerve?",
        "Option 1":"Recurrent branch of median",
        "Option 2":"Superficial ulnar nerve",
        "Option 3":"Deep ulnar nerve",
        "Option 4":"Deep branch of radial nerve",
        "Option 5":"Posterior interosseus nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Deep ulnar nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 25 year old rugby player suffered fracture of medial epicondyle during a game. Which of the following muscles will not be affected?",
        "Option 1":"Flexor digitorum profundus",
        "Option 2":"Flexor carpi ulnaris",
        "Option 3":"Adductor pollicis",
        "Option 4":"Pronator teres",
        "Option 5":"Medial 2 interossei",
        "Correct Answer":"Pronator teres"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Following a thoracotomy, a patient complains of numbness and loss of fine control of the left hand. On examination, it is established that the numbness is on the ulnar border of the hand and involves the little finger and both sides of the ring finger. The hand is weak including both the abductor pollicis brevis and the first dorsal interossei muscle. Which of the following is the most likely site of neurological injury?",
        "Option 1":"Lower trunk of the brachial plexus",
        "Option 2":"Median nerve",
        "Option 3":"Middle trunk of the brachial plexus",
        "Option 4":"Radial nerve",
        "Option 5":"Upper trunk of the brachial plexus",
        "Correct Answer":"Lower trunk of the brachial plexus"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 21 year old patient was stabbed in his upper forearm, on examination, while his palm is on the table, he can\u2019t lift his thumb off the table. On examination of proximal phalanges of the thumb, the patient cannot still fully move his interphalangeal joint. What is the expected cause?",
        "Option 1":"Extensor pollicis longus tendon tear",
        "Option 2":"Radial nerve",
        "Option 3":"Median nerve",
        "Option 4":"Abductor pollicis longus",
        "Option 5":"Ulnar nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Radial nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 26-year old patient sustained an upper limb trauma resulting in a comminuted proximal forearm fracture. On examination, he can\u2019t flex his elbow and there is  altered sensation on the lateral aspect of the forearm. Which nerve root is responsible for the lesion?",
        "Option 1":"C5",
        "Option 2":"C6",
        "Option 3":"C7",
        "Option 4":"C8",
        "Option 5":"T1",
        "Correct Answer":"C6"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 29 year old patient fell from his motorbike. He is fully conscious and alert but appears to be in remarkably increasing pain. On examination , he can\u2019t flex his elbow joint with altered sensation on the lateral side of the right arm. What is the most likely diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Anterior dislocation of the shoulder",
        "Option 2":"Brachial plexus injury",
        "Option 3":"Dislocated elbow with ulnar nerve damage",
        "Option 4":"Fracture of the surgical neck of the humerus",
        "Option 5":"Supracondylar fracture of the humerus with median nerve damage",
        "Correct Answer":"Brachial plexus injury"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 12 years old child suffered a glass injury just proximal to the distal palmer crease. On examination, there is loss of proximal joint flexion of the thumb. What is the expected associated lesion?",
        "Option 1":"Loss of sensation over the whole palmer aspect of the hand",
        "Option 2":"Loss of sensation over the medial one and half fingers",
        "Option 3":"Loss of sensation over the dorsal aspect of the lateral three and half fingers",
        "Option 4":"Loss of sensation over the palmer aspect of the thumb and lateral two and half fingers",
        "Option 5":"Loss of sensation over the whole dorsal aspect of the hand",
        "Correct Answer":"Loss of sensation over the palmer aspect of the thumb and lateral two and half fingers"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 22 year old patient presented with a laceration over the volar aspect of the wrist. He is scheduled for exploration of the wound. What is the likely relation of ulnar artery at the wrist?",
        "Option 1":"Anterior to the ulnar nerve",
        "Option 2":"Ulnar to the ulnar nerve",
        "Option 3":"posterior to the ulnar nerve",
        "Option 4":"radial to the ulnar nerve",
        "Option 5":"none of the above",
        "Correct Answer":"radial to the ulnar nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"a 46 year old patient presented with parathesia on the medial side of the arm. His investigations revealed presence of a pancost tumor. What is the expected root compression?",
        "Option 1":"C8",
        "Option 2":"C6",
        "Option 3":"C7",
        "Option 4":"T3",
        "Option 5":"T1",
        "Correct Answer":"T1"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 52 year old female is in the postoperative clinic after right mastectomy. She complains of weak right hand grasp as she cannot lift her suitcase, but she can write by thumb and index. What is the expected nerve injury?",
        "Option 1":"Posterior cord",
        "Option 2":"Anterior interosseus",
        "Option 3":"Medial brachial plexus",
        "Option 4":"Recurrent median nerve",
        "Option 5":"Ulnar nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Medial brachial plexus"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 23 year old male presented after a surgical procedure shown in the picture. He complains of sensory loss over the palmer aspect of the thenar eminence, thumb and index with thenar muscle wasting. What is the most accepted cause of this presentation?",
        "Option 1":"Median nerve injury proximal to the flexor crease",
        "Option 2":"Median nerve injury distal to the flexor crease",
        "Option 3":"Ulnar nerve injury",
        "Option 4":"Recurrent median nerve injury",
        "Option 5":"Anterior interosseus nerve injury",
        "Correct Answer":"Median nerve injury proximal to the flexor crease"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which structure forms the lower border of the quadrangular scapular space?",
        "Option 1":"Teres major",
        "Option 2":"Teres minor",
        "Option 3":"Triceps long head",
        "Option 4":"Triceps lateral head",
        "Option 5":"Humerus",
        "Correct Answer":"Teres major"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 62 year old patient presented with a lateral forearm sensory loss after an RTA. Which muscle action is expected to be affected ?",
        "Option 1":"Forearm pronation",
        "Option 2":"Forearm supination",
        "Option 3":"Elbow extension",
        "Option 4":"Wrist flexion",
        "Option 5":"Fingers adduction",
        "Correct Answer":"Forearm supination"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 12 years old boy falls on his outstretched hand while riding his bike. On examination he has tenderness in the floor of the anatomical snuffbox. Xray confirmed a displaced scaphoid fracture, and the orthopedic surgeon decides that it needs surgical fixation. Regarding the anatomy of the scaphoid bone, which part of this bone is at risk of avascular necrosis?",
        "Option 1":"Distal end",
        "Option 2":"Lateral border",
        "Option 3":"Proximal end",
        "Option 4":"Medial border",
        "Option 5":"Anterior aspect",
        "Correct Answer":"Proximal end"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the exact type of the 1st carpometacarpal joint of the hand",
        "Option 1":"Condyloid",
        "Option 2":"Hinge",
        "Option 3":"Pivot",
        "Option 4":"Saddle",
        "Option 5":"Ellipsoid",
        "Correct Answer":"Saddle"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A patient sustained a motor bike accident during a marathon. Which of the following would indicate a proximal lesion with the poorest prognosis?",
        "Option 1":"Absent biceps reflex",
        "Option 2":"Erb\u2019s palsy",
        "Option 3":"Loss of sensation over the dorsum of the hand",
        "Option 4":"Lost elbow flexion",
        "Option 5":"Weak hand grip",
        "Correct Answer":"Erb\u2019s palsy"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 33 years old athlete sustained a stab injury causing a laceration 2 cm proximal to flexor retinaculum presented with parathesia over the lateral palmer three and half fingers and over the thenar eminence. On motor assessment, he has a restricted thumb movements with weak wrist flexion and abducition. Which of the following the most likely responsible injury?",
        "Option 1":"Ulnar nerve",
        "Option 2":"Median nerve & posterior interosseus nerve",
        "Option 3":"Median nerve & recurrent branch of median",
        "Option 4":"Median nerve & flexor carpi radialis tendon",
        "Option 5":"Abductor pollicis muscle & flexor pollicis muscle",
        "Correct Answer":"Median nerve & flexor carpi radialis tendon"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 32 year old man sustained an upper limb trauma. On examination, he has mild claw hand of the little and ring fingers with loss of sensation over the medial 1\/3 if the hand. Which of the following the most likely responsible injury?",
        "Option 1":"Osteoarthritic elbow",
        "Option 2":"Cervical rib",
        "Option 3":"Axillary mass",
        "Option 4":"Ulnar nerve injury at wrist",
        "Option 5":"Deep ulnar nerve injury",
        "Correct Answer":"Osteoarthritic elbow"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which of the following muscle group is the component of the rotator cuff?",
        "Option 1":"Supraspinatus, infraspinatus, teres minor & Deltoid",
        "Option 2":"Infraspinatus, supraspinatus, deltoid & teres minor",
        "Option 3":"Supraspinatus, infraspinatus, teres major & subscapularis",
        "Option 4":"Teres minor, infraspinatus, supraspinatus & subscapularis",
        "Option 5":"Subscapularis, supraspinatus, Deltoid & Teres major",
        "Correct Answer":"Teres minor, infraspinatus, supraspinatus & subscapularis"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 32 year old man sustained an upper limb trauma. On examination, he has lost medial sensation at the forearm. Which of the following the most likely responsible injury?",
        "Option 1":"T1 nerve root",
        "Option 2":"Ulnar nerve",
        "Option 3":"Median nerve",
        "Option 4":"Musculocutaneous nerve",
        "Option 5":"Posterior interosseus nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"T1 nerve root"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 21 year old patient sustained a radial fracture during a fight. On examination, while his palm is on the table, he can\u2019t lift his thumb off the table. On fixing of proximal phalanges of the thumb, the patient cannot move his interphalangeal joint. What is the accepted cause?",
        "Option 1":"Extensor pollicis longus tendon tear",
        "Option 2":"Extensor pollicis brevis tendon tear",
        "Option 3":"Median nerve",
        "Option 4":"Abductor pollicis longus",
        "Option 5":"Adductor pollicis brevis",
        "Correct Answer":"Extensor pollicis longus tendon tear"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 32 year old patient presented to emergency department after a fall. Upon examination, he is unable to internally rotate and adduct his shoulder. Which rotator cuff muscle is responsible for internal rotation of the shoulder?",
        "Option 1":"Supraspinatus",
        "Option 2":"Subscapularis",
        "Option 3":"Teres major",
        "Option 4":"Teres minor",
        "Option 5":"Deltoid",
        "Correct Answer":"Subscapularis"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 43 year old patient presented with positive tinel\u2019s sign. He reported hand pain at night along the palmer aspect of the index and middle fingers. Which muscle is expected to be preserved?",
        "Option 1":"Abductor pollicis brevis",
        "Option 2":"3rd, 4th lumbricals",
        "Option 3":"Flexor digitorum profundus",
        "Option 4":"Flexor digitorum superficialis",
        "Option 5":"Flexor carpi radialis",
        "Correct Answer":"3rd, 4th lumbricals"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A surgeon is due to perform a mid-humeral shaft fracture fixation while he found a nerve passing posterior then lateral to the humeus. The nerve then passes anteriorly at the lateral condyle. What is the expected descriped nerve?",
        "Option 1":"Radial nerve",
        "Option 2":"Median nerve",
        "Option 3":"Ulnar nerve",
        "Option 4":"Anterior interosseus nerve",
        "Option 5":"Posterior interosseous nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Radial nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which tendon lies in the third compartment of extensor retinaculum?",
        "Option 1":"Extensor pollicis longus",
        "Option 2":"Extensor pollicis brevis",
        "Option 3":"Abductor pollicis brevis",
        "Option 4":"Flexor pollicis brevis",
        "Option 5":"Adductor pollicis",
        "Correct Answer":"Extensor pollicis longus"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 43 year old sportsman is brought by ambulance post traumatic. On examination , his vital signs are normal while he cannot abduct his shoulder. Sensory testing denotes parathesia over the lateral aspect of the arm and forearm. Which nerve is most likely to be involved?",
        "Option 1":"Suprascapular nerve",
        "Option 2":"Upper trunk of brachial plexus",
        "Option 3":"Axillary nerve",
        "Option 4":"Radial nerve",
        "Option 5":"Lower trunk of brachial plexus",
        "Correct Answer":"Upper trunk of brachial plexus"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 2 year old child is assessed after lung surgery. His sensory examination is unremarkable, but he is unable to push himself from crawling to standing position due to right arm weakness. Which of the following structures would be injured?",
        "Option 1":"Thoracodorsal nerve",
        "Option 2":"Long thoracic nerve",
        "Option 3":"Intercostobrachial nerve",
        "Option 4":"Medial pectoral nerve",
        "Option 5":"Lateral pectoral nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Medial pectoral nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Radial nerve course is mainly posterior all through its course. At which anatomical spot of the following does the radial nerve travel from posterior group to anterior group?",
        "Option 1":"Spiral groove",
        "Option 2":"Cubital tunnel",
        "Option 3":"10 cm above radiocapitular joint",
        "Option 4":"1 cm above the insertion of biceps",
        "Option 5":"None of the above",
        "Correct Answer":"10 cm above radiocapitular joint"
    },
    {
        "Question":"An 80 year old man dislocates his shoulder and got it reduced in the emergency department at review three weeks later, he is unable to initiate abduction of his arm, which nerve is most likely to be injured?",
        "Option 1":"Lower subscapular",
        "Option 2":"Upper subscapular",
        "Option 3":"Axillary",
        "Option 4":"Suprascapular",
        "Option 5":"Lower trunk of brachial plexus",
        "Correct Answer":"Suprascapular"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 43 year old patient suffered a wrist injury. During examination, the patient showed prominent claw hand. Paralysis of which muscle is responsible for this deformity?",
        "Option 1":"1st and 2nd lumbricals",
        "Option 2":"3rd and 4th lumbricals",
        "Option 3":"Flexor digitorum superficialis",
        "Option 4":"Flexor digitorum profundus",
        "Option 5":"Flexor carpi ulnaris",
        "Correct Answer":"3rd and 4th lumbricals"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 43 year old patient presented with positive tinel\u2019s sign. He reported hand pain at night along the palmar aspect of the index and middle fingers. Which muscle is expected to be preserved?",
        "Option 1":"abductor pollicis brevis",
        "Option 2":"3rd and 4th lumbricals",
        "Option 3":"Flexor digitorum profundus",
        "Option 4":"Flexor digitorum superficialis",
        "Option 5":"Flexor carpi radialis",
        "Correct Answer":"3rd and 4th lumbricals"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Following a supraclavicular LN dissection a 43 year old male patient is unable to shrug his left shoulder. Which of the following deformities would be expected?",
        "Option 1":"Loss of forearm flexion",
        "Option 2":"Inability to rotate the face towards the right side",
        "Option 3":"Inability to rotate the face towards the left side",
        "Option 4":"Loss of sensation over the upper lateral shoulder",
        "Option 5":"Inability to shrug the other shoulder",
        "Correct Answer":"Inability to rotate the face towards the right side"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which muscle originates from the lower lateral border of the scapula?",
        "Option 1":"Teres minor",
        "Option 2":"Pectoralis major",
        "Option 3":"Serratus anterior",
        "Option 4":"Teres major",
        "Option 5":"Trapezius",
        "Correct Answer":"Teres major"
    }
]